Inventory of the Daniel Edward Griffiths papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Daniel Edward Griffiths papers
1947-1989
84024
Griffiths, Daniel Edward, 1917-
60 manuscript boxes (24 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
The Daniel Edward Griffiths papers contain materials relating to the theory and practice of education in the United States over a period of four decades. Griffiths served for many years as Dean of the School of Education at New York University. He was a prolific writer on the subject of school administration and gave numerous speeches and lectures to administrators and teachers at many institutions in the United States and abroad.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1984.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical/Historical Note
1917 Born, Bridgeport, Connecticut
1940 Graduates from Connecticut State College
1949 Awarded master's degree, University of New Hamphire
1952 Receives doctorate, Yale University
1956 Author, Human Relations in School Administration
1959 Author, Administrative Theory
1965-1983 Dean, School of Education, New York University
1985 Appointed chairman of the National Commission for Excellence in Educational Administration
1992 Receives Roald Campbell Lifetime Achievement Award
1999 Dies
Scope and Content of Collection
The Daniel Edward Griffiths papers contain materials relating to the theory and practice of education in the United States over a period of four decades. Griffiths served for many years as dean of the School of Education at New York University. He was a prolific writer on the subject of school administration and gave numerous speeches and lectures to administrators and teachers at many institutions in the United States and abroad.
His papers include copies of his many articles and speeches on school administration, as well as correspondence relating to several monographs he wrote or edited. These writings are listed individually by title and date. There is also a large subject file in the papers, consisting largely of correspondence, papers, and reports relating to the many conferences, seminars, and workshops in which Griffiths organized or in which he participated. There are also materials in the subject file that pertain to his work at New York University, including internal studies and reports concerning various aspects of NYU's educational program.
Additionally, there are sound recordings (in box 59) of an interview with Griffiths and a speech he gave, both dating from 1983. There is also a copy (in box 60) of a dissertation devoted to a study of his writings.
Indexing Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the library's online public access catalog.
Education--United States.; School management and organization.
Collection Contents
- Speeches and writings, 1955-1983 (Box 1)
  - "Administrative Decision-Making,", 1960 (Folder 1: 1-2)
  - "Board-Superintendent-Teacher Relations: Viable Alternatives to the Status Quo,", 1966 (Folder 1: 3)
  - "Notes for Business Managers,", 1955 (Folder 1: 4)
  - "The Past, Present, but Particularly the Future of the Schools of Education,", 1968 (Folder 1: 5)
  - "The Professorship in Educational Administration: Environment,", 1965 (Folder 1: 6)
  - "Administration as Decision-Making,", 1957 (Folder 1: 7)
  - "Administrative Organization and Staffing of Large Districts,", 1958 (Folder 1: 8)
  - "Boards of Education and Their Superintendents,", 1961 (Folder 1: 9)
  - Administrative Theory, 1959 (Folder 1: 10)
  - "The Nature and Meaning of Theory,", 1960 August 24 (Folder 1: 11)
  - "Challenges and Issues in Professional Education with Particular Reference to New York University,", 1961 November 20 (Folder 2: 1)
  - The School Superintendent, 1966 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Speeches on change, 1959-1961 (Folder 2: 3)
  - Speeches on decision-making, 1959-1963 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Miscellaneous speeches, 1971 (Folder 2: 5)
  - "Selected Annotated Bibliography of Models,", 1959 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Research in Educational Administration, 1960 (Folder 3: 1)
    Correspondence only
  - "Problems in Studying Administrative Behavior,", 1961 December 13 (Folder 3: 2)
  - "Response to The Social Sciences and Administration: A Rationale by Professor Paul Lazarsfeld,", 1962 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Administrative Performance and Personality, 1962-1965 (Box 3)
    - Summary, 1962 (Folder 3: 4)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1965 (Folder 3: 5)
  - "Development of Criteria of Success in School Administration,", 1962 February (Folder 3: 6)
  - "Dimensions of Administrative Performance,", 1962 February 21 (Folder 3: 7)
  - "Professional Education in Transition,", 1962 July 6 (Folder 3: 8)
  - "The Job Performance of School Administrators: A Research Project,", 1962 (Folder 3: 9)
  - "Tools for Assessing the Effectiveness of the Educational Program,", 1962 October 27 (Folder 4: 1)
  - "Challenges and Issues in Professional Education,", 1962 December 1 (Folder 4: 2)
  - "Modern Approaches to Administration,", 1963 (Folder 4: 3)
  - "Administrative Theory, Relationships, and Preparation,", 1963 (Folder 4: 4)
  - "Profile of the School Superintendent,", 1963 (Folder 4: 5)
  - "Some Assumptions Underlying the Use of Models in Research,", 1963 (Folder 4: 6)
  - "Tasks of the Administrator,", 1969 (Folder 4: 7)
  - "Trends in the Preparation of School Administrators,", 1959 (Folder 4: 8)
  - "Organization of School Districts,", 1956 (Folder 4: 9)
  - "New Direction in School Administration,", 1957 September 25 (Folder 4: 10)
  - "Modern Approaches to Administration,", 1958 (Folder 4: 11)
  - "Education for the Seventies,", 1970 March (Folder 4: 12)
  - "Training School Administrators,", 1970 December (Folder 4: 13)
  - "What Is Systems Theory as Applied to School Administration and How Can It Be Fully Utilized?", 1970 (Folder 4: 14)
  - "Needed: An Educational Revolution for the Seventies,", 1970 January 30 (Folder 5: 1)
  - "What Happens in the Principal's Office?", 1969 February 10 (Folder 5: 2)
  - "Public Education Ten Years Hence,", 1969 February 19 (Folder 5: 3)
  - "Behavioral Science and Educational Administration,", 1964 February 16 (Folder 5: 4)
  - "Response to Change: Effective Leadership,", 1970 February 4 (Folder 5: 5)
  - "Education for Relevance in Our Times,", 1968 September 4 (Folder 5: 6)
  - "The Elementary School Principal and Change in the School System,", 1963 December (Folder 5: 7)
  - "Administrative Theory and Change in Organizations,", 1964 (Folder 5: 8)
  - Human Relations in School Administration, 1954 (Folder 5: 9)
  - "What Is Happening in the Universities?", 1970 June 14 (Folder 5: 10)
  - "Technology and Educational Administration,", 1968 October 13 (Folder 5: 11)
  - "Educational Administration in the Seventies,", 1970 March 22 (Folder 6: 1)
  - "Schools of Education,", 1968 November (Folder 6: 2)
  - "What Should the Board of Education Expect of its Superintendents?", 1963 January 31 (Folder 6: 3)
  - "Towards Educational Statesmanship,", 1963 February 1 (Folder 6: 4)
  - "Two Masters: Can They Be Served?", 1963 February 15 (Folder 6: 5)
  - "Can School Boards Evaluate Administrative Competence?" 1963 February 18 (Folder 6: 6)
  - "The Distinguishing Qualities of Superior Administrators,", 1963 February 20 (Folder 6: 7)
  - "The Role of the Modern Educator,", 1963 May 26 (Folder 6: 8)
  - "The Case Method of Teaching Administration: A Reappraisal, 1963,", 1963 October (Folder 6: 9)
  - "The Professor-His Environment,", 1964 May 8 (Folder 6: 10)
  - "The Challenges Facing Modern Educators,", 1964 June 7 (Folder 6: 11)
  - "Better School Administration Is a Matter of Theory,", 1964 Fall (Folder 6: 12)
  - "Leadership for Educational Change,", 1964 September (Folder 6: 13)
  - "Research and Theory in Educational Administration,", 1964 September (Folder 6: 14)
  - "System Theory and School Districts,", 1965 Autumn (Folder 6: 15)
  - "Teacher Mobility in New York City,", 1965 Winter (Folder 7: 1)
  - "The Preparation of Educational Researchers,", 1966 January (Folder 7: 2)
  - "Academic Freedom for Public School Teachers,", 1966 Fall (Folder 7: 3)
  - "Clarifying Responsibilities for Educational Decision-Making,", 1966 November 17 (Folder 7: 4)
  - "The Ten Most Significant Educational Research Findings in the Past Ten Years,", 1967 February 14 (Folder 7: 5)
  - "The Future of Public Education,", 1967 April 17 (Folder 7: 6)
  - "The Role of the University School of Education in the Urban Setting,", 1967 July 6 (Folder 7: 7)
  - "School Bureaucracy: Roles and Functions of School Personnel,", 1967 November 16 (Folder 7: 8)
  - "Collective Negotiations and Their Implications for the Future,", 1967 December 6 (Folder 7: 9)
  - "Can a Union Better Represent Principals?", 1968 February 28 (Folder 8: 1)
  - "Administrative Decision-Making,", 1968 May 1 (Folder 8: 2)
  - "The State of the Profession,", 1968 May 9 (Folder 8: 3)
  - "Student Power and the Future of American Universities,", 1968 May 15 (Folder 8: 4)
  - "A New Place in the University for Schools of Education,", 1967 January 16 (Folder 8: 5)
  - "Alternatives to the Present Structure of Public Education,", 1966 November 22 (Folder 8: 6)
  - "Teacher Mobility in New York City,", 1964 (Folder 8: 7-8)
  - "Lessons from London,", 1971 October 6 (Folder 9: 1)
  - "Can Critics Change the Schools?", 1973 January (Folder 9: 2)
  - "An Introduction to Risky Decision-Making,", 1974 January 8 (Folder 9: 3)
  - "Policy Aspects of Competency-Based Teacher Education,", 1974 February 21 (Folder 9: 4)
  - "NCPEA-Report on IIP,", 1974 August 19 (Folder 9: 5)
  - "Alternatives to Accreditation,", 1973 October (Folder 9: 6)
  - "Intellectualism, Professionalism and Scholarship,", 1973 May 9 (Folder 9: 7)
  - "The Elementary School Principal: Manager or Educational Leader?" 1973 May 3 (Folder 9: 8)
  - "The Future of the School of Education,", 1973 May 1 (Folder 9: 9)
  - "Significant Research Findings in Education,", 1973 March 20 (Folder 9: 10)
  - "The Tasks of an Administrator,", 1973 March (Folder 10: 1)
  - "The Next 10 Years in Educational Administration,", 1973 February 27 (Folder 10: 2)
  - "The Inner London Education Authority,", 1973 (Folder 10: 3)
  - "Lessons from London: Alternatives for American Schools,", 1974 June 20 (Folder 10: 4)
  - "Social Science and the Reform of Teacher Education,", 1972 March 1 (Folder 11: 1)
  - "Another Look at the Ten Most Significant Results of Educational Research,", 1972 April (Folder 11: 2)
  - "Accountability: A Comparative Perspective,", 1971 May 2 (Folder 11: 3)
  - "New Education for Americans,", 1971 July 13 (Folder 11: 4)
  - "Education for the Eighties,", 1971 October 8 (Folder 11: 5)
  - "School Organization: A Lesson from Britain,", 1971 February (Folder 11: 6)
  - "Changing the Culture-The New Role of Educators,", 1971 January 27 (Folder 11: 7)
  - "The Future of Graduate Professional Education,", 1971 March 31 (Folder 12: 1)
  - "Proposals for Education in This Decade,", 1971 March-April (Folder 12: 2)
  - "Some Things for Teachers to Think about,", 1971 April (Folder 12: 3)
  - "Competency-Based Teacher Education in 1973,", 1971 (Folder 12: 4)
  - "Lessons from London: Alternatives for American Schools,", 1972 April 21 (Folder 12: 5)
  - "Making Schools Livable for Students: London after the Blitz,", 1972 September (Folder 12: 6)
  - "Politics of Education-Public Schools,", 1974 September 24 (Folder 12: 7)
  - "The Role of the College of Education in Providing Educational Leadership,", 1974 September 18 (Folder 12: 8)
  - "Another Look at Research on the Behavior of Administrators,", 1977 May 16 (Folder 12: 9)
  - "Knowledge Utilization Needs of Administrators and Researchers,", 1977 April 5 (Folder 12: 10)
  - "Contemporary Theory Development and Educational Administration,", 1977 April 5 (Folder 12: 11)
  - "Discussion of Policy and Politics of Institutional Accreditation,", 1977 April 7 (Folder 13: 1)
  - "Back to the Basics?", 1977 February 12 (Folder 13: 2)
  - "The Individual in Organization: A Theoretical Perspective,", 1976 August 16 (Folder 13: 3-4)
  - "Administration of Higher Education,", 1976 January (Folder 13: 5)
  - "The Future of Education and Professional Education,", 1976 October 15 (Folder 13: 6)
  - Notes on administrative theory, 1977 (Folder 13: 7)
  - "Not Back to Basics-But!", 1976 July (Folder 14: 1)
  - "The Collapse of Consensus,", 1975 Fall (Folder 14: 2-4)
  - "Educational Administration: Theory and Research,", 1972 (Folder 14: 5)
  - "Some Thoughts about Theory in Educational Administration,", 1975 February 23 (Folder 14: 6)
  - "Preparation Programs for Administrators,", 1977 (Folder 14: 7)
  - "The Collapse of Consensus,", 1976 July (Folder 15: 1-2)
  - "What the Schools Can't Do and What They Can,", 1976 (Folder 15: 3)
  - "Union Power: Its Impact on the Quality of Education,", 1975 February 21 (Folder 16: 1)
  - "Advice to Doctoral Students about to Write a Dissertation,", 1975 February 12 (Folder 16: 2)
  - "The Collapse of Consensus and What It Means to Educational Administrators,", 1974 October 27 (Folder 16: 3)
  - "The Collapse of Consensus: Can Administrators Survive?" 1974 November 2 (Folder 16: 4)
  - "The Doctoral Candidate,", 1974 October 14 (Folder 16: 5)
  - "Intellectual Turmoil in Educational Administration,", 1979 April 10 (Folder 16: 6-7)
  - Preface to The Owl Critics by Alfred T. Vogel, 1979 August 30 (Folder 16: 8)
  - Interview, 1983 Summer (Folder 17: 1)
  - "Contemporary Theory Development and Educational Administration,", 1978 Summer (Folder 17: 2)
  - "Behavioral Science and the Reform of Teacher Education,", 1979 (Folder 17: 3)
  - "Another Look at Research on the Behavior of Administrators,", 1979 (Folder 17: 4)
  - "Accountability for What?", 1978 April 8 (Folder 18: 1)
  - "Organizational Renewal: Putting the Lid on the Garbage Can,", 1978 March 10 (Folder 18: 2)
  - "Beyond the Basics,", 1980 Fall (Folder 18: 3)
  - "Beyond the Basics,", 1980 Fall (Folder 19: 1)
  - "Doctoral Programs Must Pass a New Test,", 1978 Fall (Folder 19: 2)
  - "The Collapse of Consensus,", 1977 October (Folder 19: 3)
  - "Some Aspects of Research and Theory in Educational Administration,", 1977 August 5 (Folder 20: 1)
  - "Theory and Research in the Administration of Higher Education,", 1978 (Folder 20: 2)
  - "Evolution in Research and Theory: A Study of Prominent Researchers,", 1983 Summer (Folder 20: 3)
  - "American Education: The New Phoenix?", 1983 May 15 (Folder 20: 4)
  - "Can There Be a Science of Organizations?", 1983 April 7 (Folder 20: 5)
  - "Theories: Past, Present, and Future,", 1982 August (Folder 21: 1)
  - "What Should Be Taught?" 1981 April 4 (Folder 21: 2)
  - "What Has Been Significant in UCEA's Efforts to Prepare Educational Administrators?", 1982 May 12 (Folder 21: 3)
  - "What Has Been Significant in UCEA's Efforts to Prepare Educational Administrators?", 1982 May 12 (Folder 22: 1-5)
  - "The Management of Decline: With Special Reference to Administrative Staffs,", 1981 January 14 (Folder 23: 1)
  - "The Crisis in American Education,", 1982 Fall (Folder 23: 2)
  - "What's Wrong with Adminstrators?", 1980 September 26 (Folder 23: 3)
  - "Political Governance and Education,", 1980 December 9 (Folder 23: 4)
  - "The Crisis in Education (With Focus on the Contemporary Scene and the Need for Dedicated Teachers),", 1981 November 19 (Folder 24: 1)
  - "CADEA in Retrospect,", 1981 September 18 (Folder 24: 2)
  - "Theories: Past, Present, and Future,", 1981 March 19 (Folder 24: 3-4)
  - Transcript of talk on taxonomies, 1962 (Folder 25: 1)
  - Organizing Schools for Effective Education, 1963 (Folder 25: 2)
  - Various book reviews, 1959-1972 (Folder 25: 3)
- Datebooks, 1979-1982 (Folder 25: 4-7)
- Subject file, 1947-1983. (Box 25)
  Includes conference materials, correspondence, minutes of meetings, and reports
  - Superintendencies, 1968-1981 (Box 25)
    - Port Washington, 1968-1969 (Folder 25: 7-10)
    - Hastings on the Hudson, 1973-1974 (Folder 26: 1)
    - East Williston, 1970-1977 (Folder 26: 2-3)
    - Hartsdale, 1970 (Folder 26: 4)
    - Herricks, 1968 (Folder 26: 5)
    - Greenburgh, 1975 (Folder 26: 6)
    - General, 1968-1981 (Folder 26: 7-10)
  - Griffiths and Childress Associates, 1969 (Folder 26: 11)
  - Childress, Jack, 1968-1980 (Folder 26: 12)
  - Executive Action Letter, 1962-1969 (Folder 27: 1-2)
  - Superintendencies, 1963-1971 (Box 27)
    - Wilmington, 1963-1964 (Folder 27: 3)
    - Harrison, 1975 (Folder 28: 1)
    - Manhasset, 1970-1971 (Folder 28: 2-5)
  - Urban Education Studies workshop, 1979 (Folder 28: 6)
  - Urban Education Studies workshop, 1979 (Folder 29: 1)
  - Morgan State University, 1978-1979 (Folder 29: 2)
  - Atlanta Project, 1972-1973 (Folder 30: 1)
  - Louisiana study of doctoral programs in education, 1976 (Folder 30: 2-4)
  - Regents plan for post-secondary education, 1972 (Folder 31: 1)
  - Graduate School of Education, Rutgers University, External Review Committee, 1980 (Folder 31: 2)
  - Upper Darby School District study, 1980 (Folder 31: 3)
  - Curriculum vitae, 1962-1974 (Folder 32: 1)
  - Baylor University, 1978 (Folder 32: 2)
  - Texas College and University System, 1982-1983 (Folder 32: 3)
  - Urban Education Studies workshops, 1979-1980 (Folder 32: 4-5)
  - City University of New York-United Federation of Teachers conference, Tarrytown, New York, 1974 (Folder 32: 6)
  - University of Tennessee, 1974 (Folder 33: 1)
  - Evaluation of doctoral program, University of Massachusetts at Amherst, 1970-1971 (Folder 33: 2)
  - Visit to Washington, D. C., 1967 (Folder 33: 3)
  - Site visit to Oregon, 1967 (Folder 33: 4)
  - Education Commission of the State of New York, 1968 (Folder 33: 5)
  - Professional Institute of the American Management Association, 1971-1973 (Folder 33: 6)
  - B'nai B'rith meeting, 1975 (Folder 34: 1)
  - Association for Educational Data Systems meeting, 1967 (Folder 34: 2)
  - Site visit to New York City, 1967 (Folder 34: 3)
  - International Inter-Visitation Program, 1966 (Folder 34: 4)
  - Westchester principals meeting, 1967 (Folder 34: 5)
  - Yale post-doctoral seminar, 1967 (Folder 34: 6)
  - Meeting with Ohio deans of schools of education, 1977 (Folder 34: 7)
  - University of Nebraska at Omaha lecture series, 1977 (Folder 34: 8)
  - National Businessmen's Council meeting, 1967 (Folder 34: 9)
  - Visit to San Antonio, Texas, 1967 (Folder 34: 10)
  - Texas A&M University conference, 1967 (Folder 34: 11)
  - Site visit to Philadelphia, 1967 (Folder 35: 1)
  - Post-Bakke seminar, 1978 (Folder 35: 2)
  - Mainstreaming conference, 1978 (Folder 35: 3)
  - Conference on Performance Based Teacher Education, 1973 (Folder 35: 4)
  - White House conference, 1966 (Folder 35: 5)
  - Norwalk project, 1967 (Folder 35: 6)
  - New York University Faculty Women's Club dinner, 1977 (Folder 36: 1)
  - New York City Elementary School Principals Association conference, 1977 (Folder 36: 2)
  - American Association of Colleges for Teacher Education, 1976 (Folder 36: 3)
  - Council of Supervisors and Administrators convention, 1979 (Folder 36: 4)
  - Conference on Testing for the Selection of Teachers and Supervisors, 1979 (Folder 36: 5)
  - New York University, 1947-1975 (Box 36)
    - Annual reports, 1947-1975 (Box 36)
      - 1970-1971 (Folder 36: 6)
      - 1971-1972 (Folder 36: 7-10)
      - 1971-1972 (Folder 37: 1)
      - 1972-1973 (Folder 37: 2)
      - 1972-1973 (Folder 38: 1)
      - 1973-1974 (Folder 38: 2)
      - 1971-1972 (Folder 39: 1-3)
      - 1970 (Folder 40: 1)
      - 1947-1975 (Folder 40: 2)
    - State of the school messages, 1967-1977 (Box 41)
      - 1967 (Folder 41: 1)
      - 1968 (Folder 41: 2)
      - 1969 (Folder 41: 3)
      - 1970 (Folder 42: 1)
      - 1971 (Folder 42: 2)
      - 1972 (Folder 42: 3)
      - 1974 (Folder 42: 4)
      - 1975 (Folder 42: 5)
      - 1976 (Folder 42: 6)
      - 1977 (Folder 42: 7)
    - Annual reports, 1973-1975 (Box 43)
      - 1973-1974 (Folder 43: 1)
      - 1974-1975 (Folder 43: 2)
  - U.S. Office of Education, 1969-1971 (Folder 43: 3)
  - Teacher certification, 1964-1975 (Box 44)
    - 1964-1965 (Folder 44: 1)
    - 1972 (Folder 44: 2)
    - 1975 (Folder 44: 3-4)
  - State Education Department, 1970-1974 (Folder 45: 1)
  - New York State Deans Council, 1972-1975 (Box 45)
    - 1972 (Folder 45: 2)
    - 1974 (Folder 45: 3)
    - 1975 (Folder 45: 4)
  - Teacher Education Conference Board, 1973-1978 (Box 46)
    - 1973 (Folder 46: 1)
    - 1974 (Folder 46: 2)
    - 1975 (Folder 46: 3)
    - 1976 (Folder 46: 4)
    - 1977 (Folder 47: 1)
    - 1978 (Folder 47: 2)
  - New York University, 1978-1980 (Box 47)
    - Report on the future, 1980 (Folder 47: 3)
    - Report on the future, 1980 (Folder 48: 1)
  - Annual reports, 1978-1979 (Folder 48: 2-3)
  - Teacher Corps project, 1976-1978 (Folder 48: 4)
    - New York University, 1972-1981 (Box 49)
    - Undergraduate Education Project, 1978-1979 (Folder 49: 1)
    - Advisory Group, School of Education, Health, Nursing, and Arts Professions, 1978-1979 (Folder 49: 2)
    - Ad Hoc Committee of the Senate to Study Tenure, 1972 (Folder 50: 1)
    - Study on intercollegiate athletics, 1981 (Folder 50: 2)
  - University of Michigan, 1963-1964 (Folder 50: 3)
  - Cornell University School of Education, 1964 (Folder 50: 4)
  - Teachers College, Columbia University, 1964 (Folder 50: 5)
  - University of Chicago, 1964 (Folder 50: 6)
  - University of Wisconsin, 1964 (Folder 50: 7)
  - Joint conference of school administrators and superintendents, Grossinger, New York, 1964 (Folder 50: 8)
  - Ontario College of Education, 1964 (Folder 50: 9)
  - Workshop for administrators, Detroit, Michigan, 1964 (Folder 50: 10)
  - State University of Iowa, 1964 (Folder 50: 11)
  - Advanced Institute for School Trustees and Administrators, Toronto, Canada, 1964 (Folder 51: 1)
  - Ford Foundation meeting, 1965 (Folder 51: 2)
  - Ontario College of Education, University of Toronto, 1965 (Folder 51: 3)
  - New Jersey Council of Education meeting, 1965 (Folder 51: 4-5)
  - Manhattan Square Torch Club meeting, 1965 (Folder 51: 6)
  - University of Alberta, 1965 (Folder 51: 7-8)
  - Advanced Program in Administrative Leadership, Rockland County, New York, 1965 (Folder 51: 9)
  - State education department personnel conference, Chicago, Illinois, 1964 (Folder 51: 10)
  - Monterey County Office of Education seminar, Monterey, California, 1966 (Folder 51: 11)
  - Paoli Area High School System survey, Berwyn, Pennsylvania, 1966 (Folder 51: 12)
  - State University of New York at Buffalo, 1964 (Folder 51: 13)
  - Workshop, Plainview, New York, 1964 (Folder 51: 14)
  - Colgate University Education Department study visits, 1966 (Folder 52: 1)
  - Philadelphia Board of Public Education seminar, Philadelphia, Pennsylvania, 1965 (Folder 52: 2)
  - Center for the Advanced Study of Education conference, Ocean Lake, Oregon, 1964 (Folder 52: 3)
- Speeches and Writings, 1965-1984 (Box 53)
  - "The Meaning of Scholarship,", 1965 April 9 (Folder 53: 1)